# **BALAJI B**

#### **Address:**

No. 101, Durga Garden Extn.,

Sathumadurai Village, Adukkamparai,

Vellore District - 632 011, Tamilnadu, India.

**Mobile:** +91 7708106361

E-mail: bbalaji\_123@yahoo.co.in

balaji.b123@gmail.com

## **Objects**

Aim to be associated with progressive Organization, that gives me scope to update my knowledge and skill in accordance with the latest trends and be a part of a team that works dynamically towards the growth of the Organization and gain satisfaction there of.

#### **Education**

Class	Group	Institution	Year
M.B.A	Systems	University of Madras, Chennai	2012
M.C.A	Computer Science	University of Madras, Chennai	2007
B.Sc.	Computer Science	Annai Therasa Arts & Science College Thirukazhukunram, Chengalpattu	2003
HRS	Maths and Computer Science	St.Columbas Hr. Sec. School Chengalpattu -2	2000
SSLC	Maths and Science	St.Columbas Hr. Sec. School Chengalpattu -2	1998

**Computer Certification and Courses:** 

Class	Group	Institution	Year
Online Course	Visual Basic. Net – Programming in <b>VB.Net</b> Windows Forms and Reports	Udemy – Online Course	2022
Oracle 9i	OCA (Oracle Associates Certified) - <b>SQL, PL/SQL</b>	Directly received Certificate from Oracle through Online Exam <b>score 98%</b>	2008
Smart Start Course	Visual Basic, SQL SERVER, HTML, DHTML, C, C++	SSI Education Centre – A Grade	2003

## **Typewriting Certification:**

**English Typewriting Lower** – First Class :

> Model exam - Distinction **Higher** – Second Class

Certified Associate

**Tamil Typewriting Lower** – Distinction :

#### **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

#### IT Skills:

Category	Skills
<b>Operating Systems</b>	VMware, Windows 10 / 2008 R2 / 2012 / SCO Unix Open Server Enterprise Edition 5.0.4, RedHat and Ubuntu Linux, Altiris Server, SCCM server
Programming	VB.Net, SQL Server Report Builder 2008 (SSRS), PL/SQL, Oracle Developer 2000 Forms and Reports, Oracle 9i, Visual Studio (Visual Basic, C#, ASP), HTML, C, C++, VBA/Macros for Excel, J2EE, JSP
Database	Oracle 9i - Administration, Ms-SQL Server – 2008 to 2019, Progress 7.0, MySQL, Ms-Access – 97 to 2016, ABAP (Advanced Business Application Programming)
Backup	Avamar, CA ArcServe Backup 6.1, Symantec Backup Exec. 12D
Help Desk	Manage Engine ServiceDesk, Heat, Ivanti
E-Mail	Outlook 2007/ 2010/ O365, Fortiva, Lotus Notes R5
Tools	SQL Server Management Studio, BRIO Business Intelligence 5.5,6.6 OLAP, Apache Tomcat 5.x, Ms-Visio 2007/10, Ms-Lync 2013, Ms-Office Communicator R2 / Skype O365, Active Directory, Remote Desktop Connection Manager

#### Career Profile [Total IT Exp. 19.6+ years]

Organization : Lear Automotive India Pvt. Ltd., [Lear Corporation], Chennai

**Duration** : Apr 2012 to Oct-2021

**Company Profile** : US Based Company - Car Seat, Metal, Foam, Recliner Mfg. for Nissan, Ford, BMW, etc.

Designation : IT – ASSISTANT MANAGER (CHENNAI ORAGADAM PLANT)

**Reporting To** : Asia - IT Director

#### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

#### o IT Operations:

- Managing Production SQL Server Databases in different Windows OS server versions and Developing Reports (SSRS) for Asia Sites 11 locations for Trim and 1 for Recliner (Chennai)
- IT infrastructure deployed (Server Room, Network setup for Office and Shopfloor, etc) for Chennai Oragadam New Plant
- o Managing Windows Servers File Server, Application Server and Altris / Avamar Backup Server
- Managing Servers, Computers and Business Critical Applications as per ITSM Fundamental concepts for IT Operations.
- Helpdesk Tickets analyzing and providing resolutions for IT Operations and Shopfloor Applications to meet KPI
- o QAD ERP Support L1 and data extract from Linux server and data fetch into SQL Server for reports.
- O Develoing Macro Programs for Shop floor Production and Finance Departments' Data Extract as well to reduced Data Entry / Working Timing.
- Managing Active Directory & Application Accounts User Accounts Creation, Updation, Deletion and Distribution List and Managing runtime Execution Script for File Server Drives
- o Proactive Maintenance for HP Servers, Cisco Switches, Routers, UPS Performance for 100% uptime
- Monitoring and Implementing Control System to meet SOX Audit deficiencies and Maintaining documents for ITPM Scorecard for Monthly, Quarterly, Semi-annually and Annually Audit review
- o Managing All IT Capex & Expenses within the Budget limit

- License Tracking for All Software and Assets
- Maintaining all Backups (SQL Server Database, File Server Data) and Managing DRP
- Managing Network LAN / WAN / Cisco Router / Firewall / Switches / PoE switches
- Managing Shopfloor MES Applications
- LPBS Projects Development and Deployment Application Projects [Asia Champion]:

#### **Development: VB.Net. SOL Server and SSRS Reports**

- O Lear Production Board System [LPBS] Development, Deployment and Enhance Auto Generate PBS Reports
  - INDIA:
    - Sewing Trim Plants Oragadam (Chennai), Halol
    - EDS Wire harness Chakan
  - PHILIPPINES:
    - ELECTRICAL Lapu-Lapu
    - Wire harness
       Gabriella (Cebu)
  - CHINA:
    - Sewing Trim Plant Shenyang (Shanghai)
    - Sewing Trim Plant Yangzhou
  - INDONESIA:
    - Sewing Trim Plant Cikarang (Jakarta)
  - MALAYSIA:
    - Sewing Trim Plant Tanjung Malim
  - VIETNAM:
    - Sewing Trim Plant Donson (Hai Phong Vinfast)
  - THAILAND:
    - Sewing Trim Plant Korat (Kabinburi)
- LPBS GEMBA Application [Shopfloor Dashboard]:
  - o PHILIPPINES:
    - Wire harnessGabriella (Cebu)
  - o INDIA:
    - Sewing Trim Plants Oragadam (Chennai), Halol
    - EDS Wire harness Chakan
  - O VIETNAM:
    - Sewing Trim Plant Donson (Hai Phong Vinfast)
- O Development:
  - As customer requirement, 2D Barcode Label design for Master Sample, Operator Badge using Zebra Designer, Bar Tender software to connect with SQL Server DB – India Chennai, Halol(in Nov'2012), Vietnam Donson (in Dec'2020) Plants.
  - o PBS[Production board System] Dashboard Programs Developed using Excel Macro with SQL Server to display Productivity, Downtime, Defects, etc for Shop Floor 72" Monitor Display. This program will

Retrieve data in every 15 sec once and automatically will change the Sheet every 5 sec once for Bar Chart, Pie chart, etc. in Nov'2012

- Data retrieve from FORD website without login by using Excel Macro program. Before coming LJS application in Nov'2013
- ASSET MANAGEMENT SYSTEM (AMS) VB.net with SQL Server Database developed as based on ITIL Fundamental concepts to Track History of Assets, Individual person assets, Warranty, AMC Renewal, Assets Age for replacement, etc., and Reports development in SQL SSRS in Apr'2017

Organization : Tyco Valves & Controls India Pvt. Ltd., [Tyco International], INDIA - Chennai

**Duration**: July 2005 to Apr 2012

**Company Profile** : US Based Company - International Manufacturing Services Division, Valves Mfg.(100% EOU)

**Designation** : SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

**Reporting To** : Global Business Application Manager - Singapore

#### Job Responsibilities:

## o IT Operations:

- Managing Servers Windows Servers and SCO Unix server
- Managing Legacy Symix ERP application with Progress DB
- O Data Extraction to SAP R/3 for implementation
- o Reduce IT Service Calls as Incidents, Problem, Change management using ITIL concepts
- o Backup and Restore from SCO Unix Server
- Supporting to 2 Manufacturing Plant (Guduvancherry & Halol) and 7-Sales Offices (Chennai, Kolkata, Mumbai, New Delhi, Pune & Vizag) in India
- o Active Directory User Accounts Management, Group Management
- Structured OU implemented in the Active Directory for Guduvanchery Factory OU
- Maintaining Active Directory and McAfee ePO Server

#### o Program Development:

- o Development & maintenance of reports & queries in Symix ERP using Progress Database
- Development of windows scripts for Windows performance management and IT Asset Inventory.
- o Maintaining Assets, Software Licenses and CMDB
- Deploy Automatic generating reports for Data Clarity and to reduce users work time using VBA programs
- o Managing Applications Saral Paypack, Cadem ShopTrack, AutoCad Inventor 2011 and TycoCore

Organization : Lifestyle International Pvt. Ltd., INDIA - Chennai

**Duration** : Aug 2003 – July 2005

Company Profile : Dubai Based Landmark Group Company – Retail Showroom

**Designation** : IT – Assistant

Reporting To : Oracle Application Manager – Chennai

## Job Responsibilities:

## IT Operations:

- o Managing Oracle databases for Chennai Warehouse and Showroom
- Managing BOSS Application (Back Office Sales System Developer 2000, Oracle 9i and WINDOWS NT)

#### Program Development:

- Enhancing MIS & SMR reports for Warehouse and Showroom Managers for India sites.
- Developing in BRIO Business Intelligence Reports for different locations data analysis
- Developed Visual Basic Application with Oracle 9i and deploy as Installation setup package for other site
   Data correction / Modifying
- Updating Sales and Stock details Oracle Database for different locations for India sites.

#### **Personal Details**

Date of Birth : 17-July-1982

Marital Status : Married Sex : Male

Languages Known : English & Tamil

Passport Number : J5783173

Person with Disability : Locomotor Disability

DATE:

PLACE: (BALAJI B)